Hello and welcome to the Amazon Web Services Iot section.
In this section, we'll configure the project to enable communication with a US Iot core, which is
a cloud service that will allow us to communicate with the ISP from anywhere.
And in our implementation, we'll go through the basic processes of Iot core and from the AWG dashboard
we'll subscribe to and publish the temperature and humidity sensor data as well as the received signal
strength of our local Wi-Fi connection.
Okay, so in this lesson, I'll just provide a high level brief introduction to a WSI Iot core, and
then I'll share some a WC Iot core resources that are beneficial when first getting started, which
should also help with clarifying more technical details.
And just as a heads up in the next lesson, I'll discuss a few technical topics that should provide
even more clarification.
I'll also mention the ESP, AWB Iot SDK, which will integrate into the project and also provide the
AWB account setup link.
And then at the end I'll mention the steps it will take for our public subscribed implementation and
testing using the MQ t test client.
All right.
So for now, let's continue with the AWB Safety Overview and to visualize AWB Iot Communication at a
very basic level.
We'll have our thing as it's called in AWB, which is our device that will connect to the cloud via
AWB Iot core using the NQT protocol, which is a lightweight published subscribe protocol compatible
with a society.
I'll touch on this more in a bit.
Now let's review some basic information about a U.S. Safety Corps.
The U.S. Safety Corps is a platform that connects Iot devices to US, Iot services.
And to get started, let's go through some key resources for US safety.
And I would first suggest that you follow this link to the US Iot Getting Started page as it's worth
going through all of this information because there's much to learn regarding a society, which is why
I also suggest going to the learn more about a website link and bookmarking it for future reference.
And if you're looking for additional resources regarding technical aspects, I also suggest watching
this introduction to a WSU tee and just follow the link and you can log in with your Amazon account.
And this is a really good introduction to the basics where each of these components are described.
And in fact, I would even come back to this after we've completed the project setup if you really want
to nail it down.
However, for now, let's just continue with the basics here.
A WSU core includes the device gateway, which enables devices to communicate with a WSU securely and
efficiently in the device.
Gateway supports NQT web sockets and HTTP 1.1 protocols, and the device Gateway hosts a message broker
which connects and processes messages between your Iot device and the cloud.
The message broker is a published subscribe broker service that allows you to send messages addressed
to a topic like the topic I've created here, which we'll use later.
So the act of sending the message is referred to as publishing and the act of registering to receive
messages for a topic filter is referred to as subscribing.
And in this course we'll use the muted test client here to monitor muted messages being passed into
Amazon Web Services accounts from the ESP 32.
So the ESP 32 will publish imputed messages that are identified by topic to communicated state to a
WSU team and will also subscribe to messages on the ESP 32 side and test sending them using the published
to a topic option here.
So publishing and subscribing using the MQ test client is a good way to get started with a society.
And once you've done this, you can then dive deeper on your own.
And just briefly about nQt.
nQt is a lightweight, published subscribed network protocol that transports messages between devices.
To learn more about Iot core communication protocols and the details of each, you can use the FWC Iot
device communication protocols link here where you can examine the details and capabilities of each.
And the next link is quite useful for learning more about using MQ with a society.
And you'll find that there are two different levels of quality of service available.
Quality of service level zero messages are sent zero or more times and should be used for messages that
are sent over reliable communication links or that can be missed without a problem.
And quality of service level one messages are sent at least one time and then repeatedly until the public
response is received.
And you'll see how the different quality of service options are used and implemented in the source code.
Now let's take a look at how we're going to enable AWG sale TE Core communication on the ESB 32.
So of course we're going to use IWC or TE, but I wanted to point out that SB 32 supports multiple cloud
frameworks.
So if you're interested, you can follow the additional links here to get started with the basics for
any of these frameworks.
For example, Google Iot provides its own examples that you can get started with.
And they provide a getting started guide for theirs as well.
All right.
So that's all I'll mention about that.
Now let's go back to IWC.
The ESP 32 IWC sale team is based on Amazon Web Services, Iot Device SDK and embedded.
See which you can find here and we'll set this up in the next lesson.
But first, you'll need to set up your IWC Iot account.
So let's review the process.
You can use the link here to set up your account.
And the process is the typical registration process.
You'll just provide your email address and create an account name, confirm it and create a password,
and then into your name, phone number and address and credit card information for identity verification
purposes.
And then you'll see a message like this when doing so.
And then you may need to verify your identity with your phone number as well.
And the whole process should take around 5 minutes.
And I'll also just mention that when I signed up, I chose the basic support free plan.
And you could check out details when you get to this part.
And then once you're done, you can always get back to the management console via the link here.
So feel free to bookmark this one as well.
Now let's talk about the implementation and configuration steps that we'll take.
First, we're going to clone the ESP WC Iot repository and add it to the project by updating the CE
make list file in the project directory.
And then we'll add the template files that are provided in the resources for this section and we'll
include them into the project build by updating the CE make list file under the main folder and then
we'll go into the Iot core management console and create a thing in Amazon Web Services.
And we'll also create a policy and attach it to the device certificate and then we'll generate the certificates
in public and private keys, and then we'll need to add the certificates and private key as embedded
components on the East Side.
Then we'll update the source code to accommodate the AWG Iot Freitas task and adding the Iot core component
will increase our application size, so we'll need to adjust the partition table accordingly.
Well then update the SDK config to include the device data endpoint from your Amazon Web Services account.
And then we can flash to the ESB 32 connected to the Internet and subscribe and publish data to and
from the RWC dashboard.
And I also just want to mention that we'll use our connected event callback function and main that C
to start the US Iot free task as we want to kick off that task when the ESP is connected to the internet.
And as a second step we'll get the received signal strength indicator of the Wi-Fi connection using
the ESP Wi-Fi to get AP info API and will publish it to a WSU team.
This will enable you to monitor the health of the connection from anywhere and then also will publish
the temperature and humidity sensor data.
All right, so be sure to set up UAW Society Core Account and LC as soon.